I sigh
早上一醒来
when I wake up in the morning.
就会先叹口气
At some point, it became a habit.
这不知不觉成了我的习惯
Isn't love…
明明恋爱…
…supposed to be more fun than this?
应该是更开心的事才对
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Wow…
真厉害
You're right on time.
准时抵达
I didn't think you'd be here early.
我没想到你早就到了
-Sorry. -It's fine.
-不好意思 -没关系
Surely…
我想…
I'm about to be…
我接下来…
rejected.
一定会被甩吧
You know,
我啊
I've liked you since our freshman year.
从高一就喜欢山田同学了
Did you notice?
你有发现吗？
-No. -That figures…
-没有 -我想也是
I've tried hard to keep you from noticing.
因为我都有藏好自己的感情
"Please don't let him find out."
“希望不会被你发现我的心意”
It's all I ever thought about.
我满脑子只想着这种事
I guess all that…
想必今天
ends today.
就是最后了吧
But when I woke up, I realized
但我今天醒来后
that I don't have to pretend anymore.
想到不必再假装自己其实不喜欢你
Then I felt a little relieved.
就感到轻松多了
And that's why…
所以我…
I don't regret it.
一点也不后悔
-There are some things I'd like to say. -Sure.
-希望你可以听我说 -好的
I like the way you play.
我很喜欢你的游玩风格
As a gamer, I mean.
就是打电玩的事
You always keep your cool and you never lash out.
你非常冷静，也不会责怪人
When it comes to player vs. player,
在玩连线游戏时
a lot of people lose their temper.
很多人容易玩到暴跳如雷
-But you never act that way. -Right…
-但你从来不会那样 -是哦
I admire that maturity.
我很崇拜你这种成熟性格
Thanks.
谢谢
Also, when you drift off in class,
然后你待在教室发呆时
I like how you always look out the window.
盯着窗外的模样，我也很喜欢
Oh, and I didn't want to seem like everyone else, so I never told you…
怕你以为我在跟风，我也从没说过
But I've always thought you have a handsome face
但我一直觉得你真的长得很帅
and I like the way you don't show it off.
从不引以为傲的态度我也喜欢
Oh, and your voice too.
还有声音我也喜欢
It's really soothing.
听起来很稳重嘛
And your quiet nature.
也喜欢你的寡言个性
The way you walk, the way you run…
走路和跑步的模样我也喜欢
and your slow speaking pace too.
慢慢说话的样子也很喜欢
When you're at a loss, you have a habit of blinking, right?
你困扰时习惯猛眨眼睛吧？
There! I like that a lot too.
就是那样，我也好喜欢这一点
And I really like how you're equally kind to everyone.
也喜欢你对大家一视同仁地亲切
Over the last three years,
这三年来
I'm sure a lot of girls have liked you,
一定有很多女生喜欢上山田同学
but I have no doubt that none of them liked you as much as me.
可是不管怎么想 我都觉得自己是最喜欢你的人
I swear it.
我保证
In all the world,
我是世界上…
I liked you the most!
最喜欢山田同学的人
I can't… see him clearly.
视线好模糊…
But…
但是
I said it all.
我全都说出来了
It was weighing me down like lead.
这份感情就像铅一般沉重
It hurt for so long.
一直让我感到好难受
That's why…
所以…
I know I won't regret this.
我一点也不会感到后悔
What a relief.
痛快多了
Tsubaki,
椿同学
I…
我…
I'm afraid…
我没有办法…
I can't return your feelings.
回应你的感情
Right…
嗯
I'm sorry.
对不起
I…
我…
There's something
你的手上…
on your hand.
有什么…
This is…
这个是…
An acquaintance was playing around…
刚才我朋友开玩笑画的
I know…
画图的人…
who it was.
我知道是谁
It's the girl…
是山田同学…
you like,
喜欢的人
isn't it?
对吧？
Yes.
是的
Thank you for feeling that way about me.
谢谢你愿意喜欢上我
I'm sorry
无法有所回应
I can't do the same.
真的很抱歉
It's fine.
没关系
I'm happy that you listened to me.
很高兴你愿意听我说
I'm glad I told you.
幸好有说出来
I knew, you know.
我都知道
I've been watching all this time.
因为我一直看着你
Even if it was tiny…
你有稍微
I saw a change in you.
变得和以前不太一样
Even if no one else noticed,
即使没有任何人发现
I knew it right away.
但我立刻就察觉到了
I feel better having said everything.
全说出来就痛快多了
Thank you for your time.
谢谢你拨时间给我
I'll head home now.
那我回去了
See you at school.
之后学校见了
Uh… um…
那…那个…
should I walk with you?
我送你回家吧
Your glasses are broken and it's dark too.
你现在没戴眼镜，天色又暗
-It's fine. I'll go alone. -But…
不用，我一个人回去
I'll be fine.
没事的
I'm stronger than you think!
我才没那么娇弱
Right.
了解
Thanks.
谢谢你
You were kind to the very end.
你到最后还是对我这么温柔
I'm glad.
我真的很高兴
I really liked that about you.
我最喜欢你这一点了
I really liked you.
最喜欢你了哦
I do have a break from school,
学校现在虽然放假了
but my part-time job schedule is up in the air.
但打工的班表还不确定
Oh, is it loud?
很吵吗？
Sorry, I'm getting ready to go out.
抱歉，我正准备要出门
We're having a guild meeting.
是游戏公会的聚会
No, not a school club.
不是社团啦
I told you before, didn't I?
我之前解释过了吧？
My online gaming friends…
就是游戏网友
Yeah, them.
对
We're going out for dinner together.
我和那群人约了吃饭
YAKINIKU BARBECUE RESTAURANT
（多幸烧肉）
I think I see her.
她好像来了
-Look! -Oh, you're right!
-在那边 -真的耶
Akane!
茜
RUNA!
（瑠奈你好）
-Long time no see, Mr. Kamota. -What will we have?
-鸭田先生，好久不见了 -你想吃什么肉？
Thank you so much for coming!
谢谢你来参加
-No, thank you for inviting me. -Can we order spare ribs?
-我才要谢谢你们约我来 -牛五花？要吃什么肉？
-Spare ribs? -Spare ribs sound good.
-牛五花？ -真想吃牛五花耶
Spare ribs for me!
瑠奈也要吃牛五花
-Spare-ribs! Spare-ribs! -Huh? Where's Yamada?
-牛五花… -奇怪？山田不在
The one you're looking for will be late.
秋斗要晚点才会来哦
Hi there!
你好
You startled me! Hi!
吓我一跳，你好
Shall I set up some time alone for you two?
要不要想办法让你们独处？
He's been busy lately,
那家伙很忙
and there's little time to meet, right?
你们没什么机会见面吧？
In the end, I didn't get the chance to ask him out!
话说我上次其实没有告白啦
Don't worry about it.
不用啦
Tonight I came for the barbecue.
我今天是专程来吃肉的
-Welcome! -Are you sure?
-欢迎光临 -是吗？
We have a reservation under Kamota.
我有预约，敝姓鸭田
We've been awaiting your arrival, Mr. Kamota!
久候多时了，鸭田先生
Plus…
而且…
Yamada seems pretty tired lately.
总觉得山田最近好像有点累
It must be stress from studying for exams.
大概是有大考的压力吧
I doubt that.
那不可能吧
He barely has to study for a good score.
大考对他来说根本轻轻松松
Is that true?!
是那样吗？
Then was it just my imagination the other day?
他上次的疲态只是我的错觉吗？
This place looks expensive!
感觉是间好贵的店哦
Will it be expensive meat too?
肉会不会很贵？
-Runa, please keep your voice down. -Why?
瑠奈，你小声一点哦
LOVES BARBECUE
（最爱肉了）
My friend owns this place.
这里是我朋友开的店
It just opened last month.
上个月才刚开幕
They've been asking me to come, but I thought it would be more fun
他一直邀我来光顾，机会难得
if we all came together!
我就想和公会成员一起来
Really?
原来是这样
I guess you have lots of connections, Mr. Kamota.
鸭田先生的人脉真广耶
President Kamota!
鸭田社长
It has been too long.
别来无恙了
Oh, Inoue!
井上老弟
You look well.
你看起来过得不错嘛
Yes, and you look the same, sir.
是的，社长看上去也很有精神
Is business going well?
生意还顺利吗？
Thanks for your support.
托您的福，还算过得去
Oh, President Kamota!
哎呀，鸭田社长
You're here too?
原来你在啊
Oh, Mr. Obayashi! Hello!
大林大师，你好啊
President Kamota! Fancy seeing you here!
鸭田社长，好巧哦！
Chairman Nagaoka! How nice to see you.
长冈会长，你好呀
Oh, if it isn't Mr. Kamota!
是鸭田先生，吓我一跳
Ms. Sumiyoshi, nice to see you.
住吉社长的太太，你好啊
How amazing that you're all here!
实在是太巧了啊
Um, that's a bit too many connections.
不…人面也太广了吧
Just how important is he?
鸭田先生是何方神圣？
Wow! We got a private room!
欸！瑠奈我们是坐包厢哦
Oh, that's so good!
肉好好吃
It always tastes better with a lot of people.
和大家一起吃，又更加美味了
I was sorry to hear the new member couldn't come.
新人无法一起来，真是可惜啊
I invited her, but it seems she had other plans.
我有邀了她，但她好像没空
Who needs her?!
她不来也没差！
Excuse us.
打扰了
This is on behalf of Mr. Inoue.
这是对面包厢的井上先生送的
This is from Mr. Obayashi.
这是大林先生送的
This is from Mr. Nagaoka.
这是长冈先生送的
This is from Ms. Sumiyoshi.
这是住吉女士送的
I HOPE THEY DIDN'T SPEND TOO MUCH…
（感觉真不好意思）
Oh no, I guess they felt obligated.
哎呀，让大家费心了啊
There's sake too! Wow!
连酒都有！好强！
I've never seen this happen in real life before.
第一次看到其他客人请客的场面
This is so cool!
好好哦
I wanna become a big man like you one day, Mr. Kamota!
我也想成为鸭田先生这样的大人物
What are you talking about?
你胡说什么啦？
You're already a fine young man.
瑛太你已经很了不起了啊
I'm only able to hunt in the dungeon without worry
我能那么悠闲地待在地下城打怪
because you take care of all the guild work.
全都多亏有你担下公会的工作
That's only because you support me behind the scenes.
因为有鸭田先生在背后支持我啦
That's not true!
才没那回事啦
You always set the stage for me to have fun
你总会为我们打造融洽的环境
and introduce me to so many good friends.
让我认识了好伙伴
Every day is truly fun.
我每天都过得很开心哦
I hope we can continue to have fun together for a long time.
希望今后能继续和大家一起玩
I agree!
人家也懂！
I want the guild to stay as it is now, forever!
瑠奈也想永远和现在的成员一起玩
As it is now!
“现在”的成员就好
As it is now… forever…
永远…和现在一样…
Then again, change is necessary too.
但有时候也是需要变化啦
I'll keep letting fresh air in once in a while.
今后也会继续有新人加入
Huh? I'm absolutely against it!
不行！坚决反对！
Why can't things stay as they are?
为什么不能维持现况就好？
Have no fear of change!
不要害怕改变
I was grilling that piece!
那是瑠奈烤的肉耶！
That may be,
那是你这么想
but since I'm the one who raised you,
但瑠奈是我照顾长大的
it's as if I grilled it myself.
这块牛五花也算是我烤的
You are so annoying, Eita!
瑛太好烦！
HIGH-GRADE RICE WINE
（田米酒造株式会社）
Welcome!
欢迎光临
You must be a part of Mr. Kamota's party.
是鸭田先生的朋友吧
I'll show you to your table.
我来带路
The babysitter is here!
监护人来了
-Akito, you're late! -Evening.
-秋秋好慢哦 -你们好
-We've been waiting for you! -Yamada, get this!
-等你很久啦，秋斗 -山田，听人家说啦
Runa's really had her hands full!
刚才瑠奈累死了啦
-I thought you were coming earlier? -I'm so worn out!
-你不是说可以早点来吗？ -真的是累翻了
Um, hold on…
-那个… -我说啊
-Akito, here's the menu. -It was hard work!
-秋斗，菜单在这边哦 -瑠奈真的很辛苦哦
-There are lots of options. -Are you listening?
-肉有很多种哦 -你有在听吗？
-Don't all speak at once… -I'm serious!
-大家不要同时说话… -瑠奈我说真的
Oh no, she's back!
糟糕，她回来了
Hey look, it's Yamada!
是山田
What the…
什么…
Why is she so drunk?
为什么这个人会醉成这样？
It's my fault for encouraging her to try all the sake we were given.
我不小心推荐她尝尝别人送的酒
You're not at fault here!
这不是鸭田先生的错
Akane never knows when to stop!
谁叫茜要喝得一口接一口
I've had to deal with her the whole time. It was so annoying!
她一直那样缠着瑠奈，超烦的
Akane gets fairly giddy when she's drunk, it seems.
小茜一喝酒，就会变得好开朗哦
I CAN'T TAKE ANYMORE!
（瑠奈要改改那种 爱排挤外人的个性哦）
She's all yours, Yamada.
山田，后续就交给你了
If she gets on your nerves, you can leave her
觉得烦的话，就放她到厕所不管
in the bathroom like I did.
人家刚才就是这么做
Um, I'd rather not.
不，我很困扰
Akito! Sit and enjoy the meal.
秋斗，坐下来吃饭吧
I'll arrange a taxi for Akane, later.
我之后会叫出租车送小茜回去
There's no need for that.
不用啦…
Akito will walk Akane home.
让秋斗送Akane回去就好 别担心
Are you sure?
是吗？
Yup!
没错
-How ya doin'?! -Well, they do get along well.
-有精神吗？ -他们两人的确很要好啦
I guess we can leave it to him?
那就交给他好了？
Hey…
真是的
Whart took you sho long, Yarmada?
你很慢耶，山田
Sorry.
不好意思
Delicious!
好好吃！
We're better off hitting on girls here.
附近找个女生搭讪一下好了
-Definitely. -There are some cuties walking around.
-我赞成 -有没有可爱的女生呢？
-It's water. -Huh?
-这是水 -奇怪？
Oh no, was I asleep?!
糟糕，我刚才在这里睡着了？
Yes.
是的
I can't believe it.
难以置信
Neither can I.
我也有同感
Oh, wow! Water!
是水！
I was really thirsty!
我现在正好超渴的
How did you know I needed water?
你怎么知道我想喝水？
You made that very clear.
你刚才就吵着要喝水
In fact, you sang it.
还大声唱出来
Thirsty, thirsty, I'm so thirsty!
喉咙干巴巴的
This must be the desert!
这里是沙漠吗？
I'm sorry for the trouble!
真抱歉，给你添麻烦了
I swear I won't forget what you've done for me!
我会努力铭记这份恩情
I just never seem to remember what happened while I was drunk.
我总是记不清楚喝醉时的事
I know, I'll write it down!
对了，记下来就好
If it's in my phone, I'll always know!
写在手机里就安心了
You can forget. Let's just go home.
忘了也没差，我们回去吧
It's already late.
已经很晚了
It's true! Look at the time…
真的耶，已经这么晚了
Say, Yamada… this far is fine.
欸，山田，你送到这里就好
You don't have to walk me all the way home.
要是送我到家，会很绕路
It's not safe. I'll go with you.
太危险了，我送你到家
There are a lot of drunks around here.
这附近的醉鬼也很多
Other than you, that is.
除了茜以外的醉鬼
Sorry, my heel is stuck.
抱歉，我的鞋跟卡到了
Oh man, it won't budge.
糟糕，拔不出来
Um…
那个…
I'm really sorry for taking up your time.
抱歉哦，这么麻烦你
It has penetrated the surface.
插进地面了
Got it--
拔出…
Shall we go?
我们走吧
I'll be going then.
那我送到这了
Sleep well.
辛苦了
Thanks!
谢谢
Be safe getting home.
回去要小心哦
Hey!
欸
Um…
那个…
Y…
山…
Yamada, do you like me or something?
山田你是不是…喜欢我？
Huh?
奇怪…
Oh, I uh…
没有啦，就是…
Somehow, I just got that feeling.
只是有这种感觉啦
After all…
因为…
His hand…
你的手…
I guess I've been caught.
露馅了吗？
His hand against mine…
牵着我的那只手…
Uh, um…
那个…
…seemed to be saying so.
一直像在这么说着
I'm… still drunk.
我现在…喝醉了
Am I making sense?
我想问的意思
Do you understand what I--
你有听懂吗？
I like you.
我喜欢你
I like you, Akane.
我喜欢茜
I don't mind
明天起床后
if you forget when you wake up.
你就算忘了也没关系
I'll come tell you again.
我会再来跟你说的
Until you remember.
直到你记起来为止
Good night.
晚安了
Tomorrow…
明天…
YAMADA WITH THE AFRO?
（爆炸头山田？）
When I wake… in the morning…
早上起床后…
WHO ARE YOU?
（你是谁？）
Can I call you?
可不可以打电话给你？
WELL, ROMANCE ISN'T ALL WINE AND ROSES, ANYWAY
（反正谈恋爱也不全是开心的事）
I'm sure I'll worry
我一定会以为自己在做梦
that this was all a dream. So…
心里会觉得很不安
SOUNDS MISERABLE
（真凄惨耶）
Can I…
可以打电话…
do that?
给你吗？
I'll call you.
我会打给你的
Tomorrow…
等到明天
When I wake in the morning.
早上起床后
Hello?
喂？
Good morning.
早安
Good morning!
早！
HASN'T SLEPT A WINK
（一晚也没睡的人）
So, what happened next?
然后呢？
What did you talk about?
你们在电话里说了什么？
Tell me everything! Word for word!
给我全部招来，一句不漏
Some things are secret.
我当然不能说啊
You have a new boyfriend?
茜交到男友了啊
That's great!
恭喜你了
-What's he like? -Wait a minute…
-难不成在朋友之中 -什么样的人？我们学校的？
-Am I the only single one, now? -He's a senior in high school.
-只有小桃我没男友？ -不是，是高中生
DESPITE ALL THOSE BLIND DATES
（联谊…我明明每天都这么努力）
Oh, a younger man.
年纪比你小啊
Yeah.
嗯
I have trouble with younger men though.
我不太擅长和年纪小的相处
Really?
是这样吗？
I can't help but feel that they want a mature woman
感觉对方在寻求成熟的女性
and stop showing my lighter side…
让人无法自然地撒娇啊
A MATURE WOMAN?
（成熟的女性？）
I was told they couldn't figure me out
听到他说不知道我在想什么
and since then, I've found younger men difficult.
就觉得年纪小的人好难懂
But I'm sure you'll be all right, Akane!
但我觉得茜不会有问题的啦
That's your only reassurance?
有够事不关己的口气
Better you than me.
就是事不关己嘛
Oh, no you don't, Akane!
等等，茜
No stressing out when I'm the single one!
别在单身的我面前沮丧啦
-IT'S SO UNFAIR!! -MATURE WOMAN
（成熟的女性 太不知好歹了！）
Sorry.
不好意思
Whatever.
算了
For what it's worth, I knew you'd end up together sooner or later.
反正我早就知道你们迟早会在一起
Really?
是吗？
Yeah. I could just tell.
-嗯，就是有那种气息 -气息？
Was it that obvious that I was after him?
我对山田的攻势有那么明显吗？
I DON'T KNOW HOW I COME ACROSS
（自己都没有发现…）
No…
没有啊
It was the opposite.
是相反啦
And so, what I'm trying to say is…
然后啊，所以我想说的就是
you have exams soon, right?
山田就快大考了嘛
I'm sure you'll be short on time,
我猜你没什么时间了
so you don't have to worry about me.
你真的不用太顾虑我
I'll do my best not to be a burden on you.
我也会小心不带给你负担
But every once in a while…
但是有时候
When you're tired, perhaps…
假如你偶尔觉得累了
You can depend on me for support.
你也可以依赖我…
At least pretend to listen!
你至少假装听一下啦
No, I was listening.
不，我有在听啊
Up to "the kanji for person is really two people holding each other up."
听到“人这个字是彼此扶持”
That was pretty early on.
有够前面的耶
After that, I wasn't sure what you were trying to say
后面我就听不太懂你想说什么
and when I watched your lips moving up and down,
看着你一直张口说话的模样
I noticed your canine teeth are pretty sharp.
就发现你的虎牙还蛮尖的
Huh?!
虎牙？
I thought it was cute, so I kept looking.
因为满可爱的，就一直在看了
Cute?!
可爱？
You're teasing me!
你在捉弄我吧？
No, not at all.
不，没有啊
MATURE WOMAN
（成熟的女性）
SO MUCH FOR THAT
（算了）
I don't think "mature woman" will work for me.
好像无法好好维持成熟的形象
I'll walk you home.
我送你回家
Thanks.
谢谢
-In the end… -Yes?!
-所以… -什么？
What did you really want to tell me?
你刚才到底想说什么？
HASN'T STOPPED THINKING
（一直在思考）
Well…
这个嘛
In other words…
也就是说…
when we're walking together,
走在一起的时候
I'd like to hold hands.
我想和你牵手
Sorry.
抱歉
Isn't there an easier way to say it?
你的表达方式会不会太难懂了？
I'll work on it.
我会改进的
Please do.
麻烦你了
Is that… a shoe?
这是…鞋子吗？
I think it's a shoe.
应该是鞋子没错吧？
Can something like this function as a shoe?
真的有发挥鞋子的功能吗？
No, that's the reason why
不，就是没有
she ended up like that.
才会变成那样吧
If it leaves them face down on the street,
既然会像这样趴在地上
why not wear normal shoes?
不如穿双好走的鞋子吧
I don't get women.
女人还真难懂
Are you okay?
你没事吧？